# **DENNIS AWER MENSAH**

Phone: +233 267048905 |E-mail: dennis.mensah.awer@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennisawermensah/ | GitHub:https://github.com/dennisawermensah

## **PROFILE**

A Cloud Solutions Architect with hands-on experience in using over 10 cloud products in AWS Cloud to design, build, deploy and maintain a well-architected frameworks for business needs. Dennis is client-centric and intentional about improving quality through agile-built systems in any organization.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Azubi Africa

## **Solutions Architect Trainee**

Jan. 2022 - April 2022

- Built, deployed and tested 30 projects in the AWS Cloud through the Well-Architecture Framework.
- Designed and launched to provision 5 virtual environments and databases in the cloud.

## **People's Pension Trust**

Dec. 2021 - Jan. 2022

## **Data Analyst**

- Successfully eliminated over 20% error in data through Python.
- Added 3 more effective strategies to bring value to over 52,000 customers.

## **Turkish Healthcare Travel Council**

May 2021 - Aug. 2021

## **Data Analyst**

- Reduced cost of logistics by \$348.00 through data analysis in Power BI.
- Increased partnerships by 20% by implementing analysis from MS Excel dashboard.

## **University of Ghana Medical Centre**

May 2021 - Aug. 2021

## **Health Service Administrator**

- Increased the management of fleet by 5% through accelerated communication.
- Positively impacted over 300 patients through AIDET.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Ghana

Jan. 2021 - 2024

BA Health Services Administration & Psychology.

**University of Ghana** 

Sept. 2021 - March 2015

BA French, Spanish & Linguistics.

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Azubi Africa

**April 2022** 

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.

**Blossom Academy** 

Jan. 2021 - 2024

Ghana AI Fellowship.

Virtually Testing Foundation `

Oct. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Penetration Testing.

#### SKILLS

Language: French - Fluent, English - Fluent, Spanish - Basic, Chinese - Basic.

**Technical:** AWS EC2, ECS, EKS, S3, Lambda, VPC, Azure, Fargate, Ansible, Terraform, CloudFormation, Git, CI/CD, Python, HTML, CSS, Ubuntu, Linux, Docker, MySQL, Excel, PowerPoint, Bash Scripts.

**Soft:** Strong communication skills, collaboration, team player and leader, detailed, organized, fast learner, adaptable.